presencehealth.org 2017-12-10

# Privacy Policy Chicago, Illinois (IL) - Presence Health

### Presence Health's Notice of Privacy Practices

### Web Site Privacy Policy

The information on this website is provided by Presence Health. While we try to keep the information as accurate as possible, we do not imply any warranty or representation about its accuracy or completeness, or appropriateness for a particular purpose. By using the Presence Health website you assume full responsibility for using the information at this site, and you understand and agree that Presence Health is neither responsible nor liable for any claim, loss, or damage resulting from its use. The mention of specific products, services, or providers at this site does not constitute or imply a recommendation or endorsement by Presence Health, unless it is explicitly stated.

**Accountability**

Presence Health considers it your right to know whom this website represents. For this reason, we want you to know that Presence Health operates under the sponsorship of five congregations of Catholic women religious:  Franciscan Sisters of the Sacred Heart, Servants of the Holy Heart of Mary, Sisters of the Holy Family of Nazareth, Sisters of Mercy of the Americas and Sisters of the Resurrection.

You can be assured that the information you receive on our website is legitimate and not subject to any conflict of interest, as this web site does not accept advertising.

**Links Referenced Out of the Site**

Presence Health does not endorse, and is not responsible for the content of any web sites you reach through an external link, all of which are all maintained by others. If you try one of these links you will leave the Presence Health website, but can return with your browser's "back" button.

**Medical Disclaimer**

Presence Health will try to ensure that the information provided on its official websites is accurate, timely and useful. However, in view of the possibility of changes in medical sciences, neither the authors nor Presence Health nor any other party who has been involved in the preparation or publication of the information warrants that the information is in every respect accurate or complete, and they are not responsible for any errors or omissions or for the results obtained from your use of such information. You are encouraged to confirm the information with other sources.

Medical information presented on the Presence Health website is for educational purposes only and should not be used for diagnosing or treating a health problem or a disease, nor is it a substitute for professional care. Should you have any health care related questions or suspect you have a health problem, you should consult your health care provider. If you think you may have a medical emergency, call your doctor or 911 immediately.

**Trademark, Copyright and Restrictions on Use**

This site and its contents are subject to copyright. The copyright is owned by Presence Health, or in the case of some material, a third party. You may view this site and its contents using your web browser and electronically copy and print hard copies of parts of this site solely for personal, non-commercial use. Any other use, including the reproduction, modification, distribution, transmission, republication, display or performance of the content of this site is strictly prohibited.

This site includes registered trademarks, and other trademarks that are otherwise protected by law. Except as expressly authorized, the use or misuse of any of these trademarks is strictly prohibited.

**Applicable Law**

This site is created and controlled by Presence Health. Your use of this site is governed by, construed and enforced in accordance with the laws of the State of Illinois, U.S.A. Disputes arising from your use of this site are exclusively subject to the jurisdiction of the courts of Cook County, Illinois, United States of America.

This site may be accessed throughout the United States and overseas. Presence Health makes no representations that the content of this site complies with the laws (including intellectual property laws) of any country outside the United States. If you access this site from outside the United States, you do so at your own risk and are responsible for complying with the laws in the place where you access the site.

**Privacy Policy**

Presence Health cares about your privacy, and for this reason, carefully controls the information you provide to us when you visit our website.

  * **Ways We Use Personal Information You Send to Us**  
If you elect to contact Presence Health via email or through the Presence Health website, the information you provide will not be sold to any third parties. In all other respects, Presence Health does not collect personal information without your knowledge. Please note that when you contact Presence Health through this website, the information you send will not be encrypted unless otherwise noted. Therefore, people who are actively attempting to intercept web transmissions may be able to read information you send to us. However, we have installed a number of security measures to protect the confidentiality of your personal information. We have a firewall to prevent unauthorized access to our systems. Once the information is sent to our sites, it is kept on a separate database not available to users on the Internet and protected to the fullest extent reasonably possible.

We may use your personal information, with the assistance of third parties, to track the effectiveness of our web site efforts and to generate health care related materials. Additionally, we may disclose information when legally compelled to do so.

  * **Why We Pay Attention to How You Use Our Web Site**  
In order to understand how you use our web site, we analyze our website's traffic. In this process, we track which pages you visit and in what order, how you entered the site and how long you remain here. We never associate this information with your personal identity or any individually identifiable information about your computer system.

This information is used in aggregate to help us improve our site and make it more useful to you.

  * **How We Collect Information on Your Use of This Site**  
The Presence Health website utilizes a standard technology called "cookies" and web server logs to collect information about how our web site is used. A "cookie" is a small line of text that is stored with your web browser when you visit a cookie-enabled web site. The text may contain a random identification code or user preferences. Your browser has options that allow you to control whether the browser accepts cookies, rejects cookies or notifies you each time a cookie is sent to you.

Cookies help us collect important business and technical statistics. The information in the cookies lets us trace the paths followed by visitors to our web sites as they move from one page to another. Web server logs allow us to count how many people visit our web sites and evaluate our web site visitor capacity. We do not use these technologies to capture your individual e-mail address or any personally identifying information about you.

**Contacting the Web Team**  
If you have any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of the Presence Health website, or your interaction with the Presence Health website, contact us at [webteam@presencehealth.org](mailto:webteam@presencehealth.org).
